HAI DANG

Doctoral HCI Researcher h.dang@uni-bayreuth.de

I'm a Ph.D. candidate at the university of Bayreuth and part of the HCI+AI research group. My work focuses on conceptualizing and building new tools to enable non-expert users to continuously interact with generative models and craft new things with the help of deep learning models.

EDUCATION

University of Bayreuth, Bayreuth Germany

2020/09 - 2024/07

Doctor of Philosophy

Department of Computer Science

LMU Munich, Munich Germany

2018/10 - 2020/07

Master of Science

Department of Computer Science

GPA: 3.7 — (German Scale: 1.23)

Thesis: Representational Learning for Exploring

Input Spaces in HCI

LMU Munich, Munich Germany

2013/10 - 2018/07

Bachelor of Science

Department of Computer Science

GPA: 3.7 — (German Scale: 1.38)

Thesis: Deep Conformance Checking

Efficient Estimation of Alignment Based Fitness.

Yonsei University, Seoul South Korea

2016/08 - 2017/07

Bachelor of Science

Department of Computer Science

 $Year\ Abroad$

TECHNICAL STRENGTHS

Python Libraries PyTorch (primarily), Pandas, Numpy, Tensorflow Programming Languages: Python (primarily), JavaScript / Typescript, Java

Web-Frameworks: React, D3js, Flask / FastAPI

DevOps: Docker, Nginx, Git

OS: Unix Systems (primarily), Windows (occasionally)

PUBLICATION

Hai Dang and Daniel Buschek. 2021. **GestureMap: Supporting Visual Analytics and Quantitative Analysis of Motion Elicitation Data by Learning 2D Embeddings.** In *Proceedings of the 2021 CHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems (CHI '21)*. Association for Computing Machinery, New York, NY, USA, Article 317, 1–12. DOI: https://doi.org/10.1145/3411764.3445765

UNIVERSITY PROJECTS

Representational Learning for Exploring Input Spaces in HCI

SS20

Master Thesis

- · Developed an interactive tool to analyze and visualize gesture elicitation studies in HCI.
- · Used a VAE to learn a two-dimensional gesture space from depth images recorded with a Kinect Sensor.
- · Conducted expert interviews to evaluate the tool.

Ensemble Knowledge Graph Embedding

Seminar: Group Project

- · Reimplemented ConvE (Dettmers et al. 2018) and improved computation time by 30% by using adequate vectorization.
- · Managed and monitored the machine learning models and the remote training clouds using MlFlow and DVC.

Evaluation of Consumer Grade BCI Devices

SS 2019

Seminar: Group Project

- · Applied basic signal processing techniques on the raw EEG recordings to extract the alpha and theta frequencies that characterize the cognitive workload.
- · Trained multiple classifiers from the SciKit library to differentiate between various workload levels.

Development of an Interactive Sleep Monitoring Device

SS 2019

Seminar: Group Project

- · Built the analytics backend to collect and analyze sleep data.
- · Designed the communication protocol between the device and the analytics backend.

Power Efficient High Performance Computing

WS 2018

Seminar: Group Project

- · Developed a recurrent neural network model for the prediction of energy consumption.
- · Achievement: Won the class competition for most accurate predictions by employing an autoregressive recurrent neural network.

SELECTED WORK EXPERIENCE

SWM, Munich

2019/08 - 2019/11

Machine Learning Developer

Working Student

- · Collected and integrated electricity data from various transmission system operators
- · Implemented multiple autoregressive models to predict feed-in-management operations
- · Built and deployed an end-to-end machine learning solution

Celonis, Munich

2017/10 - 2019/02

 $Software\ Developer\ /\ Data\ Scientist$

Working Student

- · Responsible for the Python Data Push API for the Celonis Business Intelligence Cloud Platform.
- · Developed a pipeline to programmatically analyze event data.
- · Developed business analyses and gave data science workshops
- · Developed tools to automate and administrate the Celonis Process Mining Platform

SELECTED RELEVANT COURSEWORK

Data Processing and Analysis: Deep Learning Algorithms, Machine Learning, Knowledge Discovery in Databases, Probability and Measure Theory, Big Data Management

Human-Computer-Interaction: Advanced topics on HCI, Intelligent User Interfaces, Human-Computer-Interaction

General Software Development: Data Structures and Algorithms, Software Architecture, Software Testing, Agile Development

WS 2019